{
    "id": "63baad0dbf114225ae886f13cfd5b815",
    "title": "Simple, Complex, Compound",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "8435763cad684712984c7e51dbd05ade",
            "title": "Simple, Complex vs. Compound",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In spite of his hard work, he could not score good marks.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "As soon as we heard the gunshots, we rushed indoors.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "When I opened the door, the cat jumped out.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "His remarks angered me but I said nothing.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Though it was a holiday, I went to work as usual.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If it rains, I will open the umbrella.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She passed the test because of her hard work.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He failed despite his hard work.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It has been several months since we last met.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are in trouble because of your stupidity.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one finite verb and one clause in it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She opened the book and started reading.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I turned around but I didnâ€™t see anyone.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses connected by coordinating conjunctions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}